smythson.com 2012-11-19

# Privacy and Security

### Privacy Policy

Frank Smythson Ltd. are registered in England and Wales No. 3594597  
Registered Office: 40 New Bond Street, London, W1S 2DE

By using this website and/or registering with www.smythson.com (“Smythson”), you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy. This statement sets out Smythson’s data protection policy for the information that you provide to us when using this website (the “website”).

Your privacy and security is very important to us and we aim to ensure that any personal information we obtain will always be held, used and transmitted in compliance with UK data protection rules. Our payment providers, Sage Pay, are Level 1 PCI DSS compliant. All card data is transacted securely by SagePay and no card data is held by Smythson.

This Privacy Policy applies from 27th May 2011 for all use of the website after this date. Smythson may occasionally amend this Privacy Policy to reflect any changes in our information collection and disclosure practices or regulatory requirements. Any new policy will automatically be effective when it is published on the website.

Data collected and methods of data collection

You can see and amend your personal details held by us by logging in to your account. You may also contact us directly to find out this information. Your email address and password are required to view or edit your personal details online. You are responsible for keeping your password confidential.

Sending information via the internet is never completely secure. We do our best to protect your personal data, however, we cannot guarantee the security of your data.

The information we collect from is dependent on the activities you are carrying out on our website. We may collect the following information:

• Your contact information, e.g name, address, telephone number and email address,  
• Information about the products you have purchased,  
• Your purchase information, such as credit card details,  
• Navigation and click-stream data, time and duration of your visit, products viewed or searched for, items in your basket, basket abandonment, information from cookies or web beacons.

We obtain information from you when you type in your personal details (i.e. when placing an order or requesting a catalogue). We also collect data automatically as you use the website, or from third parties.

To improve your experience with us, our website uses cookies and web beacons. A cookie is a piece of data that our website automatically transfers to the hard drive of your computer or mobile device when you access the website and is used to:

• Access stored information when you log in,   
• Carry information from page to page of our website,  
• Store site preferences and the items in your shopping basket,  
• Identify whether you have visited our website previously,  
• Monitor the number of visits that you make to our website, where you browse and what you have purchased, and to offer you tailored content.

Your browser options allow you to disable cookies. You should note that if you do disable cookies, you may not be able to access all the services on this site.

Web beacons work in a similar way to cookies and allow us to monitor the behaviour of our site users. Cookies and web beacons may also be used by our affiliates and market research companies to track your browsing and purchase behaviour on our website.

The following data may be automatically collected every time you visit the website regardless of whether you are logged in: computer and connection information, browser information, operating system and platform details and time of access. We may use an IP address to identify you and to gather broad demographic information about you, which we will use to assist in the detection of fraud, to help identify problems and to administer the website.

If you have provided us with an email address, we will be able to associate this email address back to your previous browsing and purchase experiences. If you log in, then in addition, we will be able to associate your log in with your billing addresses, delivery addresses and your payment details.

Smythson may also obtain information about you directly from third parties, e.g. a new delivery address details from our carriers. To prevent and detect fraud, we may also obtain details of your credit history from credit reference agencies.

What is your information used for?

The main purposes for which we collect and store your personal information are as follows:

• Order processing  
• Delivery of products  
• Payment authorisation and billing  
• Promoting our offers and products  
• Improving the website and our service to you

We will contact you with marketing information where relevant if you have opted in to receive such communications. By registering on our site or for our complimentary wifi, you consent to the addition of your details to our email and postal (including catalogue) distribution list unless you have previously opted-out. You may opt-out of our communications at any time, although it may take a short time for any changes to become effective. Logging in will give you access to your account options where you can update your details.

From time to time, we may contact you by telephone for the purposes of market research, marketing our products (and for telemarketing) where you have consented to us doing so.

Use of your information by third parties

We will not sell your personal information to third parties. However, we do share customer and browsing information with third parties as described below. By making a purchase on the website, you consent to Smythson sharing your personal information with third parties as is necessary to process your order, for example, to banks, credit card companies and carriers. These carefully selected third parties may be in countries outside the UK.

We may form contracts with other companies to provide certain services, including credit card processing, shipping, name and address verification, database management profiling and segmentation, market research and promotions management. We provide these companies with only the information they need to perform their services. These companies are prohibited by contract from using this information for their own marketing purposes or from sharing this information with anyone other than Smythson.

To protect against the fraudulent use of credit cards, we carry out security checks on orders. These can take various forms, and may involve contacting you by telephone before your order is processed.

Smythson may disclose your personal information if necessary to comply with regulations or law or to assist with law enforcement, to enforce the terms under which you trade with us, or to protect our property and other rights.

Smythson occasionally runs competitions on the website in conjunction with third parties, where we will ask you if you would like to be contacted by the third party sponsoring the promotion about its products or services. If you opt in to this information, we will pass on your personal details.

Our website may contain links to third parties’ websites. Smythson assumes no responsibility for the privacy practices or the content of those websites.

If you access our website using a link from one of our partners’ websites, your personal details and purchase information may be shared between Smythson and that partner in accordance with our contractual relationship with that partner.

In the event that Smythson is sold, some of its assets transferred to a third party or in the case of liquidation or administration, your personal information, as a valuable asset of the company, may also be transferred. Use of your personal information will remain subject to this Privacy Policy.

For further enquiries, please contact Customer Services:

Tel: (0845) 873 2435  
Email: returns@smythson.com  
Mail: Customer Services dept, Smythson, 2 Oaktree Business Centre, Hunt’s Rise, Swindon, SN3 4TX, UK

Mon – Fri  | 9am – 10pm  
---|---  
Sat | 9am – 6pm  
Sun | Closed  
  
Frank Smythson Ltd. are registered in England and Wales No. 3594597  
Registered Office: 40 New Bond Street, London, W1S 2DE.

Last updated 27th May 2011
